

R.K.RUKMANI DEVI

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

+91 9788761047

rkdevimca@gmail.com

P Erode, Tamilnadu, India

https://www.linkedin.com/in/r-k-rukmani-devi

EDUCATION

MCA (DISTINCTION)
Annamalai University
2005-2007

PGDCA

Annamalai University 2004-2005

BA - PSYCHOLOGY Madras University 1988-1991

Certificate

Course in .Net Technologies - 2008 CMC Limited

SKILLS

C# .NET, MVC, PHP, SQL, MYSQL HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT JQUERY, AJAX, TFS, SVN, GITHUB BOOTSTRAP, KENDO UI TELERIK, ZEND

FREELANCE PROJECTS

Mindfularts

PyroTechTraders

LANGUAGE

English Tamil

Profile

Over twelve years of experience in Web Design and Development across diverse industries. Expertise in requirements analysis, design, development, testing, maintenance, enhancement, and production support. Quick learner and team player with strong leadership skills and the ability to work independently.

Experience

OPTTECH COMPUTING INC, US

Software Engineer

Jul 2014 - Oct 2019

Worked in a Granite Monuments manufacturing company software. This application manages the entire business automation like ERP. The feature of this application is admins can create any customized product as well as any process.

Tools: C# .NET, MVC, .Net Framework, Sql, Entity Framework, Bootstrap, Kendo UI, Telerik, jQuery, Ajax, TFS, AWS.

Analyzed requirements and designed UI using Bootstrap. Developed Front-end, Backend, and Middle Tier from scratch. Integrated Role manager for authentication, handled validation, product image processing, and email functionality. Implemented barcode processing across the application and created a barcode app for easy updates via mobile devices in all workstations.

DJ Software Consultancy Private Ltd, Erode

General Manager

Jan 2011-April 2012

As a General Manager, oversee daily operations, project planning, and recruitment. Ensure employee productivity and development, prepare reports for upper management, and manage client interactions to guide the development team and implementation plans.

Project Manager

Jun 2009 - Dec 201

As a Project Manager, oversee project planning, execution, and completion. Manage team tasks, timelines, and budgets. Ensure clear communication with stakeholders, address risks, and ensure project goals are met efficiently.

Software Engineer

May 2008 - May 2009

Projects (Few)

Tools : Php, MySQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax, SVN, Apache

- Multilevel Marketing
- Matrimonial Application
- Payroll Management System
- Point of Sale
- School Management System

Lecturer

Annamalai University Computer Training Center Jan 2007 - Mar 2008 Bharathiar University Computer Training Center Jan 2008 - May 2008

Served as a part-time Lecturer at the University Computer Traning Center, Erode. Taught various UG computer science courses, Assisted in enhancing student's technical skills and prepared them for industry demands.